The toys are back!
Toy Story 2 is a animation, comedy, family film directed by John Lasseter.
Andy heads off to Cowboy Camp, leaving his toys to their own devices.
Things shift into high gear when an obsessive toy collector named
Al McWhiggen, owner of Al's Toy Barn kidnaps Woody.
Andy's toys mount a daring rescue mission, Buzz Lightyear meets his match
and Woody has to decide where he and his heart truly belong.
Woody (voice), played by Tom Hanks.
Buzz Lightyear (voice), played by Tim Allen.
Jessie (voice), played by Joan Cusack.
Prospector (voice), played by Kelsey Grammer.
Mr. Potato Head (voice), played by Don Rickles.
Slinky Dog (voice), played by Jim Varney.
Toy Story 2 is a 1999 American animated adventure comedy-drama film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It is the second installment in Pixar's Toy Story franchise
and the sequel to the original 1995 film.
The film was directed by John Lasseter from a screenplay by Andrew
Stanton, Rita Hsiao, Doug Chamberlin, and Chris Webb.
Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, Don Rickles, Jim Varney, Wallace
Shawn, John Ratzenberger, Annie Potts, R.
Lee Ermey, John Morris, Laurie Metcalf and Jeff Pidgeon reprise their roles from the first Toy Story  film, with
newcomers Joan Cusack, Kelsey Grammer, Wayne Knight, Estelle Harris, and Jodi Benson joining the cast.
In the film, Woody is stolen by a greedy toy collector, prompting Buzz Lightyear and his friends
to save him, but Woody is then tempted by the idea of immortality in a museum.
Disney initially envisioned Toy Story 2 as a direct-to-video sequel.
The film began production in a building separated from Pixar, on a small scale, as
most of the main Pixar staff were busy working on A Bug's Life (1998).
When story reels proved promising, Disney upgraded the film to a
theatrical release, but Pixar was unhappy with the film's quality.
Lasseter and the story team redeveloped the entire plot in one weekend.
Although most Pixar features take years to develop, the established release date could not be
moved and the production schedule for Toy Story 2 was compressed into nine months.
Despite production struggles, Toy Story 2 premiered at the El Capitan Theatre on November 13, 1999, and was
released on November 24 to box office success, grossing $511 million against a $90 million budget.
It received widespread acclaim from critics, with a 100% rating on the
website Rotten Tomatoes, similar to its predecessor.
It is considered by critics to be one of the few sequel films superior to the original and
is frequently featured on lists of the greatest animated films ever made.
Toy Story 2 would go on to become the third-highest-grossing film of 1999.
Among its accolades, the film won Best Motion Picture –
Musical or Comedy at the 57th Golden Globe Awards.
A sequel, Toy Story 3, was released in 2010.
The film explores themes of friendship, airplane,
museum, prosecution, identity crisis.
The tone is lighthearted.